<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DATA606 - Fall 2018</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DATA606 - Fall 2018</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1</title>
      <link>/chapters/chapter1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/chapters/chapter1/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 1 - Introduction to Data Learning Objectives  Identify the type of variables (e.g. numerical or categorical; discrite or continuous; ordered or not ordered). Identify the relationship between multiple variables (i.e. indepedent vs. dependent). Define variables that are not associated as independent. Be able to describe and identify the difference between observational and experimental studies. Distinguish between simple random, stratified, and cluster sampling, and recognize the benefits and drawbacks of choosing one sampling scheme over another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation</title>
      <link>/assignments/presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignments/presentation/</guid>
      <description>You are responsible for presenting one practice homework problem during the semester. Please sign up as-soon-as possible as there are only three slots per week. Try to keep each presentation to five minutes or less. Sign-up on this Google Spreadsheet: https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1QCagC9KIhWvmSOTKmqYo0FTq1iZUdh765m7kmrqSPRc/edit?usp=sharing
GoToMeeting Connection Information:
https://global.gotomeeting.com/join/890853557
You can also dial in using your phone: (646) 749-3122
Access Code: 890-853-557</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>/course-overview/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course-overview/schedule/</guid>
      <description> Google Calendar
 Course Schedule    Start Due Date Chapter Topic     Aug-27 Sep-9 1 Intro to Data   Sep-10 Sep-23 2 Probability   Sep-24 Oct-7 3 Distributions   Oct-8 Oct-21 4 Foundation for Inference   Oct-22 Oct-28 5 Inference for Numerical Data   Oct-29 Nov-4 6 Inference for Categorical Data   Nov-5 Nov-25 7 Linear Regression   Nov-26 Dec-9 8 Multiple &amp;amp; Logistic Regression   Dec-10 Dec-12 Navarro Introduction to Bayesian Analysis   Dec-13 Dec-17  Final Exam    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2</title>
      <link>/chapters/chapter2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/chapters/chapter2/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 2 Learning Outcomes  Define trial, outcome, and sample space. Define and describe the law of large numbers. Distinguish disjoint (also called mutually exclusive) and independent events. Use Venn diagrams to represent events and their probabilities. Describe probability distributions. Distinguish between marginal and conditional probabilities. Use tree diagrams and/or Bayes Theorem to calculate conditional probabilities and probabilities of intersection of non-independent events. The expected value of a discrete random variable is computed by adding each outcome weighted by its probability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetups</title>
      <link>/course-overview/meetups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course-overview/meetups/</guid>
      <description>There will be weekly meetups. You are encouraged to attend as many as you can but recordings will generally be availabe the day after the meetup.
You can join the meetup from your computer, tablet or smartphone at: https://global.gotomeeting.com/join/890853557.
You can also dial in using your phone: (646) 749-3122
Access Code: 890-853-557
Presentation Signup Sheet
   Date Topic Resources      Intro to Course Video, Slides   Wed, Sep 5, 8:00 pm Intro to Data Video, Slides, R Script   Wed, Sep 12, 8:00 pm Probability Video, Slides   September 19 NO MEETUP - Yom Kippur    Wed, Sep 26, 8:00 pm Distributions Part I Slides   Wed, Oct 3, 8:00 pm Distributions Part II    Wed, Oct 10, 8:00 pm Foundation for Inference    Wed, Oct 17, 8:00 pm Foundation for Inference cont.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3</title>
      <link>/chapters/chapter3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/chapters/chapter3/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 3 Assignments Homework OpenIntro Statistics
 Practice: 3.1 (see normalPlot), 3.3, 3.17 (use qqnormsim from lab 3), 3.21, 3.37, 3.41 Graded: 3.2 (see normalPlot), 3.4, 3.18 (use qqnormsim from lab 3), 3.22, 3.38, 3.42  Lab The labs are available in the DATA606 R package. To start the first lab, use the startLab function. This will copy the lab to your current working directory and rename the file according to your computer username (as returend by Sys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework</title>
      <link>/assignments/homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignments/homework/</guid>
      <description>The solutions to the practice problems are at the end of the book and do not need to be handed in. Graded assignments should be typed (preferably using R Markdown) or neatly hand written and scanned. Data for the homework assignments, and for within the chapters too, can be downloaded here. Or alternatively all the data is included in the openintro R packge (use the data(package = &#39;openintro&#39;) command to list all the datasets available in that package).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Textbooks</title>
      <link>/course-overview/textbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course-overview/textbooks/</guid>
      <description>Required Diez, D.M., Barr, C.D., &amp;amp; Çetinkaya-Rundel, M. (2015). OpenIntro Statistics (3rd Ed).
 This is an open source textbook and can be downloaded in PDF format here, from the OpenIntro website, or a printed copy can be ordered from Amazon.
 Navarro, D. (2015, version 0.5). Learning Statistics with R
 This is free textbook that supplements a lot of the material covered in Diez and Barr. We will use the chapter on Bayesian analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4</title>
      <link>/chapters/chapter4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/chapters/chapter4/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 4 Assignments Homework OpenIntro Statistics
 Practice: Graded:  Labs The labs are available in the DATA606 R package. To start the first lab, use the startLab function. This will copy the lab to your current working directory and rename the file according to your computer username (as returend by Sys.info()[&#39;user&#39;]). If this is incorrect, then either provide the file-prefix parameter to startLab, or rename the file after it has been copied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labs</title>
      <link>/assignments/labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignments/labs/</guid>
      <description>These mini projects will have you explore statistical topics using R. You can use the startLab function in the DATA606 package to get started, or copy the templates from the links below. Please submit a PDF (preferred) or HTML file along with your Rmarkdown file. Be sure to answer all questions in lab, not just the on your own section. Labs can be submitted on Blackboard.
Introduction to R and RStudio (Template) Introduction to Data (Template) Probability (Template) Distributions of Random Variables (Template) Foundations for Statistical Inference Sampling Distributions (Template) Confidence Levels (Template)  Inference for Numerical Data (Template) Inference for Categorical Data (Template) Introduction to Linear Regression (Template) Multiple Linear Regerssion (Template)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>/course-overview/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course-overview/software/</guid>
      <description>We will make use of R, an open source statistics program and language. Be sure to install R and RStudio on your own computers within the first few days of the class.
 R - Windows or Mac RStudio - Download Windows or Mac version from here LaTeX - Windows use MiKTeX or Mac use BasicTeX (it is best to use Safari to download this file as Chrome or Firefox will often fail)  If using Windows, you also need to download and install these:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5</title>
      <link>/chapters/chapter5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/chapters/chapter5/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 5 Assignments Homework OpenIntro Statistics
 Practice: Graded:  Lab The labs are available in the DATA606 R package. To start the first lab, use the startLab function. This will copy the lab to your current working directory and rename the file according to your computer username (as returend by Sys.info()[&#39;user&#39;]). If this is incorrect, then either provide the file-prefix parameter to startLab, or rename the file after it has been copied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>/course-overview/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course-overview/links/</guid>
      <description>These are some useful resources on the web for learning R. Feel free to suggest other resources by clicking the &amp;ldquo;Edit page&amp;rdquo; button in the top right.
Learning R  R for Data Science. Book by Garrett Grolemund and Hadley Wickham Quick-R. Kabakoff&amp;rsquo;s website. Great reference along with his book, R in Action. O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Try R. Great tutorial on R where you can try R commands directly from the web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project</title>
      <link>/assignments/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignments/project/</guid>
      <description>Download project proposal template Download project template  The purpose of the data project is for you to conduct a reproducible analysis with a data set of your choosing. There are two components to the project, the proposal, which will be graded on a pass/fail basis, and the final report. The outline for each of these are provided in the templates. When submitting the assignments, include the R Markdown file (change the name to include your last name, for example Bryer-Proposal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6</title>
      <link>/chapters/chapter6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/chapters/chapter6/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 6 Assignments Homework OpenIntro Statistics
 Practice: Graded:  Lab The labs are available in the DATA606 R package. To start the first lab, use the startLab function. This will copy the lab to your current working directory and rename the file according to your computer username (as returend by Sys.info()[&#39;user&#39;]). If this is incorrect, then either provide the file-prefix parameter to startLab, or rename the file after it has been copied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Equations</title>
      <link>/course-overview/mathjax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course-overview/mathjax/</guid>
      <description>Occasionally you will need to type equations in homework and labs. R Markdown supports LaTeX style equations using the MathJax javascript library. I do not expect you to learn LaTeX for this course. Instead, I recommend using the free application [Daum Equation Editor](). It availabe online, as a Google Chrome Extension, or as a standalone Mac Application.
Creating Equations with Daum Equation Editor Occasionally you will need to type equations in homework and labs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7</title>
      <link>/chapters/chapter7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/chapters/chapter7/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 7 Assignments Homework OpenIntro Statistics
 Practice: Graded:  Lab The labs are available in the DATA606 R package. To start the first lab, use the startLab function. This will copy the lab to your current working directory and rename the file according to your computer username (as returend by Sys.info()[&#39;user&#39;]). If this is incorrect, then either provide the file-prefix parameter to startLab, or rename the file after it has been copied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 8</title>
      <link>/chapters/chapter8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/chapters/chapter8/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 8 Assignments Homework OpenIntro Statistics
 Practice: Graded:  Lab 1 The labs are available in the DATA606 R package. To start the first lab, use the startLab function. This will copy the lab to your current working directory and rename the file according to your computer username (as returend by Sys.info()[&#39;user&#39;]). If this is incorrect, then either provide the file-prefix parameter to startLab, or rename the file after it has been copied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian</title>
      <link>/chapters/bayesian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/chapters/bayesian/</guid>
      <description> Bayesian Analysis Assignments Homework OpenIntro Statistics
 Practice: Graded:  Lab 1 Readings  Fitting a Model by Maximum Likelihood (Collier, 2013). Kruschke&amp;rsquo;s website for Doing Bayesian Data Analysis Kruschke&amp;rsquo;s blog Andrew Gelman&amp;rsquo;s blog - Posts about bayesian statistics  Videos Bayesian Methods Interpret Data Better
 Bayesian Estimation Supersedes the t Test
 Precision is the goal
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to DATA606!</title>
      <link>/post/2018-08-27-welcome-to-data606/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-08-27-welcome-to-data606/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to DATA606! My name is Dr. Jason Bryer and I will be your instructor for this semester. In addition to teaching this course, I am an Executive Director at Excelsior College where I am currently working on a Department of Education grant to develop a Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (see www.DAACS.net for more information). Our first meeting will be on Wednesday, September 5th. Couple of important notes as you get started:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with R</title>
      <link>/post/2018-08-28-getting-started-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-08-28-getting-started-with-r/</guid>
      <description>To get started with the labs, you will need to install R and other supporting applications. Links to download all the software is on the Software page at http://data606.net/software which is available on the Misc menu. Once you are in RStudio, you will need to install a number of R packages using the following two commands:
install.packages(c(&amp;#39;openintro&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;OIdata&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;devtools&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;ggplot2&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;psych&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;reshape2&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;knitr&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;markdown&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;shiny&amp;#39;)) devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;jbryer/DATA606&amp;quot;) Note that this course used to be listed as IS 606, hence the different package name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>header</title>
      <link>/_header/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/_header/</guid>
      <description>DATA606 - Fall 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/_footer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/_footer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>